# María-Fernanda Villalobos

ma.fernanda.villalobos@gmail.com \* linkedin.com/in/marifervl \* +56 978665819

Highly motivated and easily adaptable bilingual professional with 15+ years of experience in customer services and advanced communication skills, seeking to start a IT career and expand programming knowledge. Recognised by management and peers for assertive and enthusiastic spirit. Excited to improve my career as a Full-Stack Python Developer and keen to learn by taking a MBA in the future.

#### KEY SKILLS

## IT & Technology

- Built and maintained pieces of software in Python language and Python-based frameworks.
- Created web applications in Full Stack Python and operated a database to store and manipulate data, from given technical specifications that provide solutions to the problems of the organisation.
- Good programming practices to achieve a product with quality levels in line with the needs of the industry.
- Upper-Intermediate user of MS Office, including Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Publisher and Office Lens.
- Currently studying *Django for* Everybody *Specialisation by Charles Russell Severance*.
  3 of 4 courses completed

#### **Customer Service**

- Dealt with customers in retail companies, tourism & entertainment, and health services, including complaints, offering them quick solutions.
- Managed internal customer service team to maximise selling potential and customer satisfaction.
- Kept fluent communication and feedback with staff and managers.
- Increased employee confidence and capabilities through regular education sessions resulting in improved sales and customer service.

#### Communication

- Bilingual, with Spanish mother tongue and fluent English recently improved at UKCE in London.
- Optimised writing and verbal skills, during my professional development as a speech and language therapist.
- Developed business communication skills working for the main chains of department stores in Chile.

## Problem-Solving

- Applied statistical and numerical techniques to process data.
- Assessed and analysed patient cases with structured arguments supported by evidence.
- Developed creative thinking and dependability to make strategic decisions and assertive team management in under pressure situations with shortage of resources to perform required tasks.

#### **EDUCATION**

Universidad de Valparaíso 03/2009 01/2015

**Speech and Language Pathology (BA hons)** 

#### **C**ERTIFICATIONS

Full-Stack Python Trainee - AWAKELAB Issued 06/ 2022

**Web Application Technologies and Django** - Coursera Issued 04/2022

**IELTS Academic and OET Programm**- UK College of English Issued 06/2021

#### EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Amanel

#### **Speech and Language Therapist** 02/2014 – 11/2020

- •Supervised staff and maintained health and safety standards.
- •Worked with a business partner to plan, book, and coordinate the operation of the business.
- •Interacted with customers to ensure positive feedback is received on all of our services and to incentivize them to leave a positive review on our online platforms.

#### Enjoy S.A.

#### Blackjack Dealer at the Casino M. de Viña del Mar 05/2014 - 08/2015

- •Provided outstanding customer service and personnel management in a high volume gaming environment.
- •Maintained a positive and upbeat attitude while providing customer service and demonstrating in-depth table knowledge of games and casino operations.
- •Developed quick maths skills due to all the mathematics involved with easy as well as complex casino pay-outs, and handling other customer table action.

#### Cencosud S.A.

#### Sales Associate at París (retail store) 03/2009 – 08/2013

- •Developed a quick adaptation to the increased workload generated in special sales.
- •Generated upselling and cross-selling to maximise revenue and meet branch targets.
- •Facilitated accessibility and inclusion in the purchasing process for clients with special requirements.

# Languages

# ♦ English

Professional working proficiency.

# ♦ Spanish

Native proficiency.

## Volunteering

<b>♦</b>	Staff Assistant at Hammersmith Hospital	London, UK	02/2021	06/2021
<b>♦</b>	Volunteer at Dhamma Chile and Argentina	Chile and Argentina	09/2017	04/2020
<b>♦</b>	Coordinator at Cevas	Valparaíso, Chile	12/2017	02/2018

## REFERENCES

• References are available upon request.